Guide to the R. Philip Hanes Papers, 1928-2010 RL.00503
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Personal and Boards Series, 1949?1986, undated
  - Trips: National Audubon Society Board (NY): Southeastern Center for Contemporary Art/Regional Advisory Council (New Orleans), 1977 (Box 294)
  - Trips: National Audubon Society, 1977-1978 (Box 294)
  - Trips: National Collection of Fine Arts Commission, 1976-1977 (Box 294)
  - Trips: National Collection of Fine Arts, 1979 December 6 (Box 294)
  - Trips: National Council for Arts and Education, 1977 (Box 294)
  - Trips: National Endowment for the Arts, 1977 (Box 294)
  - Trips: Nature Conservancy, 1977 (Box 294)
  - Trips: November Award, 1979 (Box 294)
  - Trips: Past Trips/Information, 1973-1974 (Box 295)
  - Trips: Scotland/England, 1973 (Box 295)
  - Trips: San Juan, 1978 (Box 295)
  - Trips: Sikkim, 1962-1971 and undated, 2 folders (Box 295)
  - Trips: Southeastern Center for Contemporary Art/Regional, 1979 (Box 295)
  - Trips: Southeastern Council on Foundations, 1978 October 25-27 (Box 295)
  - Trips: Spoleto, 1977 (Box 295)
  - Trips: Texas, 1978 November (Box 295)
  - Trips: Thanksgiving, 1979 (Box 295)
  - Trips: Tiatora, 1974-1975 (Box 295)
  - Trips: Washington, DC, 1978 December 1 and 2 (Box 295)
  - Trips: World Business Council, Inc. 1977 (Box 295)
  - Urban League of Winston-Salem: Equal Opportunity Award, 1979 (Box 296)
  - WFDD-FM, 1978-1980 (Box 296)
  - Wachovia Board, 1976 (Box 296)
  - The Walpole Society, 1973-1984, 2 folders (Box 296)
  - Wilderness Society, 1977 (Box 296)
  - Wilson, Tom: Option, 1978-1979 (Box 297)
  - Winterthur Museum, 1977, 2 folders (Box 297)
  - Winterthur Museum: Board of Trustees, 1971-1975, 3 folders (Box 297)
  - Winterthur Museum: Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 297)
  - World Business Council, 1976-1977 (Box 297)
  - Yale University Committee on Music at Yale, 1970-1972, 2 folders (Box 297)
  - Yale University Committee on Music at Yale, 1973-1974 (Box 298)
  - Young President's Organization, 1976-1977 (Box 298)
  - Young President's Organization: Boca Raton, 1975 (Box 298)
  - Young President's Organization: Correspondence, 1972-1976, 2 folders (Box 298)
- Printed Material, 1967?1979 and undated
  Includes reprints of articles, a mimeographed art magazine, and an invitation. One folder arranged chronologically.
  - Papers, 1967-1979 and undated (Box 298)
  - General, 1962-1985, 2 folders (Box 298)
  - General: "A Panic in the Pentagon," 1969 (Box 298)
  - Clippings, 1962-1983 (Box 298)
  - Picture Captions, 1960-1963 and undated (Box 298)
  - Pictures: Allied Arts Council, Sarasota, Florida, undated (Box 298)
  - Pictures: Arista Mills, undated (Box 298)
  - Pictures: Arkansas Arts Center, undated (Box 298)
  - Pictures: Arts and Science Center, Saint Paul, Minnesota, undated (Box 298)
  - Pictures: Arts and Science Museum Building, Statesville, NC, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Bahnson Co., undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Charlotte Coliseum and Ovens Auditorium, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Civic Educational Center, Saint Paul, Minnesota, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Corvallis Arts Center, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: New Orleans Cultural Attractions Fund Headquarters, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Durham Arts Center, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Federated Arts of Richmond, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Greenville Art Center, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Hanes Community Center, 1957 and undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Hanes Dye/Hosiery, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Hanes Estate, 1958-1960 (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Lakeview Center for the Arts and Sciences, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, 1962-1964 and undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Lynchburg Fine Arts Center, 1962 and undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Moravian Music Foundation, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Ogden Community Arts Council, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Old Salem, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Quincy Arts Center, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Reynolds Robacco Co., undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Roberson Memorial Center, 1960 (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Rocky Mounts Art Center, 1963 and undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Salem College, 1960 (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Sioux City Arts Center, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Tacoma Allied Arts Center, undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: United Arts Council, Inc., undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Winston-Salem Gallery of Fine Arts, 1957 and undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Winston-Salem Arts Council, 1960 and undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Winston-Salem Symphony Orchestra, 1956-1960 and undated (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Winston-Salem YWCA Building, 1960 (Box 299)
  - Pictures: Miscellaneous, 1965-1985 and undated (Box 299)
- Miscellaneous, 1960-1985 and undated, 2 containers
  Includes articles, clippings, a script for a play (comedy), and a press release. Organized into the following categories: general, clippings, and pictures. Included is a folder of picture captions.
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 298-299)
- Slides, 1965-1968 and undated, 1 container
  375 color slides of early National Endowment for the Arts meetings, 1965-1966. Some pictures are identified. In addition there are slides made in 1968, which were identified by Hanes as choice pictures from all of the trays.
  - Slides (Box 300)
- Oversize Materials, 2 boxes
  Oversize items withdrawn from other series.
  - Miscellaneous oversize (Box OV1)
  - Ampersand Casebooks: Clippings, St. John's Art Gallery, and Sawtooth Center for Visual Design (Box OV2)
  - Ampersand Company Records: Personnel Allocation by Task; Ampersand Inc. Accrued Income, 1980-1981; Financial Statements/Computer printouts, 1979, Jan.-July (Box OV2)
  - Personal Series: Roan Mountain, Hall of Justice (Box OV2)
  - Subject Files: Misc.: Westbeth Artists' Housing (Box OV2)
  - Genealogical Chart and portrait (Box OV2)
  - Ampersand-Central Files: Arts Council Action Plan, 1978 (Oversize-folder 1)
- Unprocessed Accessions, 1950s-2004, 28 boxes
  Unprocessed additions (90-060, 90-084, 92-066, 96-136, and 04-081) (5479 items; dated [1950s]-2004) include correspondence, greeting cards, subject files, financial records, reports, memorabilia, photographs, videotapes, and a large poster of Hanes' family tree. Materials reflect especially Hanes' interest in the arts, conservation (particularly in western North Carolina and Virginia), and the city of Winston-Salem. There are no boxlists for this material.
  - Acc. (1990-0084) (Box 1)
  - Acc. (1990-0060) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acc. (1992-0066) (Box 1-11)
  - Acc. (1996-0136) (Box 1-4)
  - Acc. (2004-0081) (Box 1-12)
- Accession (2010-0201), 1940-2010, 5 boxes
  Addition includes correspondence, both incoming and outgoing, as well as appointment books, clippings, and miscellaneous materials relating to Hanes' philanthropy and community involvement in Winston-Salem, North Carolina. Prominent topics include the Hanes farm and other conservation and agricultural enterprises; his role in various arts councils and arts movements throughout the city and country, including the National Endowment for the Arts; his interactions with Wake Forest University and other academic institutions; his communications with Wachovia Bank; and other issues or movements that he supported. The majority of the materials are loosely arranged in a chronological file, dating from 1940-2010 (bulk dating from 1991-2009).
  - Appointment books, 1987-2005 (8 folders) (Box 1)
  - Chronological file, 1940-2010 and unknown (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence, clippings, promotional materials, and some news or magazine articles. Arranged by year, but not within each year.
    - Early/unknown: 1940-1989 and undated (Box 2)
    - 1990 (Box 2)
    - 1991 (6 folders) (Box 2)
    - 1992 (5 folders) (Box 3)
    - 1993 (Box 3)
    - 1994-2000 (Box 3)
    - 2001 (Box 3)
    - 2002 (Box 3)
    - The Bud file, re: Wachovia Bank, 2002 (Box 3)
    - 2003 (Box 3)
    - 2004 (Box 3)
    - 2005 (2 folders) (Box 4)
      Includes a DVD of Hanes' Keynote Address at the Association of Fundraising Professionals, 2005.
    - Piedmont Triad Partnership materials, including Hanes' criticisms of MarketPlace, 2005 (Box 4)
    - The Development of Arts Councils in the USA, draft by Hanes, 2005 (Box 4)
    - 2006 (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - 2007 (Box 5)
    - 2008 (Box 5)
    - 2009 (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 2010 (Box 5)
  - National Endowment for the Arts: A History, 1965-2008, inscribed to Hanes (Box 5)